#### Contact

jan.kaiponen@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/jankaiponen (LinkedIn) github.com/janmarkuskaiponen (Other)

# Top Skills

X++

Microsoft Dynamics
Pre-sales

# Languages

Japanese (Professional Working)
English (Full Professional)
Finnish (Native or Bilingual)

### Certifications

Microsoft Dynamics® AX 2012 Trade and Logistics

Microsoft Dynamics® AX 2012 Development Introduction

Dynamics AX 4.0 - Trade and Logistics

MB-500 Microsoft Dynamics 365: Finance and Operations Apps Developer

Dynamics AX 4.0 - Financials

# Jan Kaiponen

Solutions Architect, Solutions Development Consultant Helsinki

# Summary

Jan Kaiponen tends to be thorough when working and thrives when there is a difficult problem to figure out. It comes naturally for Jan to appreciate a list of facts more than a story. Jan naturally invents things, and loves to articulate a clear plan of action before making a big decision

Jan can quickly understand business processes and is proactive in finding solutions to meet the requirements.

Jan possesses a flexible attitude as regards assuming different roles when moving from project to project. His professional experience covers requirements analysis as well as solution design and implementation during several project life cycles, and over a range of different industries.

Jan is an excellent communicator. Good at listening, too.

# Experience

#### Freelance

Solutions Architect, Development Consultant December 2011 - Present (9 years 1 month)

17+ years of experience in IT solutions development. Able to adjust to different project needs and work styles. A strong techno-functional consultant with international experience.

#### QUANTIQ

Solutions Architect July 2019 - June 2020 (1 year) London, United Kingdom

#### Avanade

Senior Consultant (Dynamics AX) December 2010 - December 2011 (1 year 1 month)

Page 1 of 2

### Logica

Consultant (Dynamics AX)
November 2008 - November 2010 (2 years 1 month)

Dubai, United Arab Emirates

### Digia Plc

Dynamics AX Consultant
December 2007 - October 2008 (11 months)

Logica (WM-data Finland)

Dynamics AX Consultant

May 2005 - December 2007 (2 years 8 months)

an MBS Partner
Dynamics AX Consultant
May 2003 - May 2005 (2 years 1 month)

University of Helsinki Teaching Assistant (Programming) 2003 - 2003 (less than a year)

# Education

University of Helsinki

Computer Science · (2001 - 2004)

SOAS University of London

BA, Japanese · (1997 - 2001)

Waseda University

International program · (1998 - 1999)

**Aalto University** 

FITech ICT · (2020)